Devil King's Army attack alert.
魔王軍襲擊警報
This is a large-scale attack.
這次的規模很大
All adventurers in the royal capital,
麻煩王都內的各位冒險者
please go to the battlefield.
都去參戰
(Konosuba Season 3)
《為美好的世界獻上祝福！ 第三季》
(Episode 5: A Bad Friend for The Princess)
(第5集 為深閨公主獻上損友)
Protect the royal capital!
保護王都
The Devil King's Army is nothing to fear.
魔王軍根本不足為懼
Are you Mr. Satou Kazuma?
佐藤和真先生嗎
I'm sorry.
不好意思
People below level 30…
30級以下的人…
It doesn't matter.
無所謂
That man has many achievements.
那個男人曾經立下許多功績
Claire.
克萊兒
I've heard of him.
我聽說過
He's the one who destroyed that Destroyer.
是他破壞了那個毀滅者
I heard that in Arcanletia,
聽說他還在阿爾坎雷堤亞
he defeated the Deadly Poison Slime, Hans.
擊敗了劇毒史萊姆漢斯喔
After all, he is the hero of Axel,
畢竟他是阿克塞爾的勇者
Satou Kazuma.
佐藤和真嘛
Kazuma…
和真…
Everyone, calm down.
大家別著急
I'm just about to become a legend.
我接下來才要成為傳說
Leave it to me, I'll do my best.
交給我吧 哥哥會加油的
Mr. Kazuma.
和真先生 和真先生
Smart as I am, I've learned my lesson.
聰明的我學到教訓了
Something is sure to go wrong in the end.
最後肯定會出什麼紕漏
For example,
比方說
someone with a screw loose will use Explosion
腦袋有問題的人使用爆裂魔法
and drag me into trouble.
害我也受牽連
Or someone with a muscle for a brain will summon monsters
或是腦袋裝肌肉的人召集怪物
Who's the one with a screw loose?
誰是腦袋有問題的人
You tell me.
妳說說看啊
Don't you dare say I have a muscle for a brain!
不准說我是腦袋裝肌肉
I want to go back to Axel.
我好想回阿克塞爾
The enemies are just small fries who win by numbers.
對手只是以數量取勝的小嘍囉們
I will show them my true abilities.
我會讓牠們瞧瞧我的真本事
Then let's go.
那我們走吧
Devil King's Army subjugation team, on the move.
魔王軍討伐隊 出發
Long time no see, Lady Eris.
好久不見 艾莉絲大人
That's not it!
不是的
Lady Eris, that's not it!
不是的 艾莉絲大人
That's right, it went well until halfway.
沒錯 直到中途都很順利
Mr. Kazuma!
和真先生 和真先生
Snipe.
狙擊
What are you doing?
妳在做什麼啊
You're a goddess, aren't you?
妳好歹也是個女神吧
How can you be defeated by a lowly Kobold?
居然被象徵小嘍囉的狗頭人打倒
How?
是怎樣啊
I'll make them regret for insulting a Goddess.
我要讓牠們為侮辱女神感到後悔
Tremble under the wrath of the deities.
在神明的憤怒之下發抖吧
Divine Light Fist.
神光拳
God Requiem!
神之輓歌
-It seems I need not worry about her. -God Requiem!
-看來不用擔心她了 -神之輓歌
Kachoufugetsu.
花鳥風月
God Requiem.
神之輓歌
A Kobold.
是狗頭人啊
For me, who has fought Leaders of Devil King's Army multiple times,
對與魔王軍幹部多次交手的我來說
you are simply not a match.
根本不夠看
Stop right there!
站住 站住
The Devil King's Army that endangers peace,
威脅和平的臭魔王軍
turn into the rust on my sword Chunchumaru…
變成這把啾啾丸的鐵鏽…
What now? This is so embarrassing.
怎麼辦 超丟臉的
Looking smug before the battle,
戰鬥前一臉得意的樣子
only to be killed by Kobolds.
結果卻被狗頭人圍攻致死
Even Lady Eris was left speechless.
艾莉絲大人也傻眼到說不出話來
You must not sexually harass others.
不可以對別人性騷擾喔
The other day, to my follower…
前幾天你對我的信徒…那個…
Lady Eris, you can see what happened on the ground.
艾莉絲大人能看見地上的情況吧
That's why…
所以才會…
No, that was unavoidable.
不 那是無可奈何喔
When I caught her,
我抓住那傢伙的時候
her chest felt flat, so I thought she was a man.
感覺胸部很平 以為她是男的
That's what happened.
事情就是這樣
I'm sorry!
對不起
I won't make any more excuses!
我不會再找藉口了
Fine.
真是的
I won't forgive you next time.
我只原諒你這次喔
Thank you.
謝謝您
Oh dear.
哎呀
I was just thinking what I should do
我剛剛還在想 要是被珍貴的經典女性角色
if a precious classic female character like Lady Eris dislikes me.
艾莉絲大人討厭了該怎麼辦
You are flattering me.
真會說好聽的話
Haven't you recently been overjoyed
你最近不是因為多了一個妹妹
by getting a new sister?
感到欣喜若狂嗎
You…
您…
Just how much have you seen?
您到底看了多少啊
Lady Eris.
艾莉絲大人
I'll stop teasing you.
惡作劇就到此為止
Actually, I have a favor to ask of you.
其實我有事想拜託你
A favor?
拜託我?
It's a task for which you won't be rewarded,
這是無法得到酬勞
nor will you gain any fame from it.
也無法得到名譽的工作
It's something I can only entrust to someone I deem reliable.
這件事只能拜託值得信賴的人
Could you help retrieve the sacred treasure?
能麻煩你幫忙收回神器嗎
Mr. Kazuma, who was killed by the Kobolds,
被狗頭人幹掉的和真先生
welcome back.
歡迎回來
Hey.
喂
Don't say that to someone who has just been resurrected.
對剛復活的人劈頭就說那種話對嗎
Let's finish the remaining Devil King's Army.
我們去收拾魔王軍的餘黨
Those who can still move, follow me.
還能動的人跟我來
Yes.
好
What should we do?
怎麼辦
Things have become tricky.
事情突然變棘手了
This Useless Goddess
看來這個廢物女神
doesn't seem to know
好像不知道
where the sacred treasure she bestowed to the reincarnated is.
她賜給轉生者的神器去哪了
The first one doesn't require a price
第一個是不需要代價
and can summon monsters at random.
就能隨機召喚怪物的神器
But controlling the monsters has a price.
但是想操控怪物需要代價
The other one allows body swapping.
另一個是能與別人互換身體的神器
This thing has a time limit for its use.
這東西有使用時間限制
It is said that these two items
聽說這兩樣東西
can have a great impact on the world
即使是轉生者以外的人使用
even if used by someone other than the reincarnated.
也會對世上造成很大的影響
I want to go home.
我好想回家
Kazuma, have you been resurrected?
和真 你復活了嗎
Yes.
對
How do you feel?
身體有沒有哪裡不舒服
Your performance just now
您剛剛的精采表現
touched me greatly!
讓我好感動
Thinking of how you resisted powerful magic
想到您一邊抵抗強力的魔法
and charged into the Devil King's Army,
一邊衝進魔王軍中央的英姿
I just…
我就…
Bring it on!
放馬過來吧
Their army commander was frightened by you.
魔王軍指揮官被您的舉動嚇到
He looked shocked.
大吃一驚的表情
It was unforgettable.
真令人難忘
No, I…
不 我…
Ka… Kazuma,
和…和真
don't push yourself.
總之你不要逞強
Rest well!
好好休息
Okay.
好
Make way.
讓開 讓開
The biggest hero is coming through.
這次的最大功臣要通過了
Clear a path.
讓開一條路
Miss Megumin is tired.
惠惠小姐累了
Wanna get blown away by Explosion?
你們想被爆裂魔法炸飛嗎
The top magician in Axel,
阿克塞爾首屈一指的魔法師
the one who turns everything to ashes,
讓一切化為灰燼的人
Miss Megumin is passing through!
惠惠小姐要通過了
What's that all about?
那是怎樣啊
It was exhilarating.
真令人痛快
Whenever the enemy commander
敵人的指揮官
is in crisis,
每次只要陷入危機
he always says that this is just the vanguard.
都會說"這只是前哨戰"
Next time, he will lead an army many times larger
"下次我會率領好幾倍的大軍"
and turn the royal capital to ashes.
"讓王都化為灰燼"
Trying to threaten us.
這種威脅的話
Just when he said that…
正讓人不爽的時候
Explosion!
爆裂魔法
I am Megumin,
我的名字叫惠惠
the top magician in Axel
阿克塞爾首屈一指的魔法師
who controls explosion magic.
操控爆裂魔法的人
You're the ones who will turn to ashes.
要化為灰燼的人是你們
Yet you countered him.
妳卻這麼說
And cast that grand spell with all your power.
用盡所有魔力 施展了那種大魔法
Right?
對吧 對吧
Facing my fatal spell,
在我的絕招面前
no one can survive.
沒有人能活下來
After all, even that Destroyer was annihilated.
畢竟連那個毀滅者都消滅了
Even that Destroyer?
連那個毀滅者都消滅了?
What a great Arch Wizard.
真是偉大的大魔導士
Miss Megumin.
惠惠小姐
Please show us other advanced magic.
請讓我們看看其他的上級魔法
I want to see too.
我也想看
I do want to show you,
我也很想讓你們看
but my magic power is depleted now.
但是現在魔力用光了
Pity.
很遺憾
No matter, you can show us tomorrow.
當然 明天再看就行了
Miss Megumin.
惠惠小姐
I'm looking forward to tomorrow.
好期待明天喔
I'll tell the others.
我去跟其他人說一聲
Tomorrow… uh…
明天…那個…呃…
Kazuma!
和真
You've successfully revived?
你成功復活了吧
You must have some trouble adjusting.
你才剛復活應該很辛苦吧
I'll take care of you tomorrow.
明天就由我負責照顧你
(Konosuba) Kazuma!
和真…
Didn't you say you'd take care of me?
妳不是說要照顧我嗎
Kazuma.
和真
Let's return to Axel tomorrow.
我們明天就回阿克塞爾吧
Early in the morning.
一大早就出發
Elder brother, I am glad you are safe.
兄長大人 幸好你平安無事
Elder brother?
兄長大人?
Ye… yeah.
是…是啊
Not exactly safe though.
不 也不能說是平安無事
Since I died and then came back to life.
因為我死了一次又復活了
Are you alright?
你不要緊吧
Before the victory celebration,
在戰勝的慶功宴開始之前
you should take some rest.
先休息一下吧
Your room has been kept just as it was, elder brother.
兄長大人的房間依然保持原樣
'Elder brother' again?
她又叫你兄長大人?
This room is really nice.
這個房間真不錯
I can understand why you didn't want to go back.
我能理解你為什麼說不想回去了
Right?
對吧
The food is delicious, and people respect me.
飯菜很好吃 走到哪都有人侍奉
If you lived here,
要是住在這裡 妳也會不想回去的
But I haven't been very active.
但我沒有什麼活躍的表現
Back to Axel tomorrow?
明天就要回阿克塞爾嗎
Although I like showing off
在王都華麗地大顯身手
in the royal capital…
雖然心情也很好
I still prefer
但我還是最喜歡
the four of us in Axel
我們四個人在阿克塞爾
completing missions together.
一起完成任務
It was a lively life, even if we quarreled.
即使吵架也很熱鬧的生活
Well… that's true.
說…說得也是
But too lively can also be a problem.
不過太熱鬧也是問題
Elder brother,
兄長大人
I am very sorry.
非常抱歉
I pleaded with Claire
我去拜託克萊兒
to let you stay in the city, but…
讓兄長大人待在城裡 但是…
There's no helping it.
那也沒辦法
I'm sorry I couldn't be of help.
很抱歉沒能幫上忙
You need not apologize.
兄長大人用不著道歉
Because you literally
因為你如字面所述
fought with your life on the line.
豁出性命去戰鬥了
Sorry.
抱歉
Your brother was besieged by Kobolds,
哥哥被狗頭人圍攻了
You two.
你們兩個
Have you forgotten that I'm here too?
是不是忘了還有我在
We haven't forgotten!
才…才沒有忘記
Iris is right.
愛麗絲說得對
How could we possibly forget?
怎麼可能忘記啊
Ah.
咦
I didn't notice before.
我剛剛沒注意到
You're wearing a powerful magical item.
妳身上戴著很強的魔法道具呢
I can feel immense magic from that necklace.
我從那條項鍊感覺到龐大的魔力
Someone offered this to my brother Jadice.
這是別人獻給傑帝斯皇兄的東西
In place of him, who is on an expedition,
代替正在遠征的皇兄
it's in my safekeeping.
由我負責保管
What kind of power does it have?
它有什麼樣的力量
Can it destroy the world?
難道是能毀滅世界的東西嗎
No, well…
不 這個嘛
We still haven't figured out how to use it.
我們還沒弄清楚它的使用方法
You are flaunting your interest.
妳張揚自己的興趣過頭了
There's a script etched on this.
這上面刻著某種文字
But the scholars in town couldn't decipher it.
但是城裡的學者好像無法解讀
Isn't this Japanese?
這不是日文嗎
Let me see.
我看看喔
What's yours is mine.
你的就是我的
What's mine is yours.
我的就是你的
Let me become you.
讓我變成你吧
Is this an insult?
是在瞧不起人嗎
You can understand this?
兄長大人看得懂嗎
This is called Japanese…
這是叫做日文的…
Hey, the necklace is glowing!
喂 項鍊在發光耶
Iris, throw it away!
愛麗絲 快丟掉
Throw it out of the window!
現在立刻從窗戶丟出去
Eh?
奇怪
Nothing happened.
什麼都沒發生呢
I thought something would happen
我還以為會發生什麼
and impact the whole world.
把全世界捲入的事情
It's disappointing.
真令人失望
How long are you going to stare at each other?
你們要互相凝視到什麼時候啊
Just like before.
剛剛也是
Don't forget that I'm here too.
你們不要忘了我也在
No, Megumin.
不 惠惠
Something shocking has indeed happened.
現在的確發生令人震驚的事吧
Calling me by my name?
突然直呼我的名字?
Listen,
我說啊
I am older than you.
我是比妳年長的姊姊
You should call me Sister Megumin.
妳應該叫我惠惠姊姊
Well…
那…那個…
I am Iris, actually.
我才是愛麗絲
Alright, what should we do next?
好了 接下來到底該怎麼辦呢
Personally, I'm willing
我個人是很樂意
to live on as a beautiful girl.
今後以美少女的身分過活
But it's also hard to separate
但原本一直跟我相伴的身體
with my old body.
也很難割捨
Why are you so calm?
為什麼這麼冷靜?
You just casually said something astonishing.
你剛剛若無其事說了很驚人的話吧
Men are really strong.
男人真的很壯很強呢
I want to go on an adventure just like this.
我好想就這樣去冒險
I'm sorry.
對不起
Speaking like this with that face…
妳用那張臉說這種話 我實在…
It's really a headache.
不過真傷腦筋
Repeating the script failed to switch us back.
試著說了剛剛的密語也沒有變回來
It can swap bodies.
居然能互換身體
Such a powerful magical item is unprecedented.
這麼強力的魔法道具真是前所未見
A magical item, huh.
魔法道具啊
If it's some sort of curse,
如果是詛咒這類的
we just have to ask Aqua…
只要拜託阿克婭…
The other one allows body swapping.
另一個是能與別人互換身體的神器
This thing has a time limit for its use.
這東西有時間限制
This is it!
是那個啊
Don't worry.
別擔心
I know what this magical item is.
我知道這個魔法道具是什麼了
This thing has a time limit.
這東西有時間限制
We'll be able to swap back.
所以我們一定能恢復原狀
Really?
真…真的嗎
I got the information from the most reliable source.
我是從最可靠的地方得到情報
Don't worry.
不用擔心
Bro… Brother…
兄…兄長大人 那個
What is it?
怎麼了
Iris, you're in the midst of puberty.
愛麗絲正值青春期嘛
Don't play with my body, okay?
不能玩弄我的身體喔
I… I wouldn't do that.
我…我才不會做那種事
I…
那個…
Just this once.
一次就好
I want to go outside the city without my retainers.
我想不帶家臣去城外
Outside the city?
去城外?
Yes.
對
It's possible with your current appearance.
用現在的模樣的確可以
But just you alone…
但是只有妳一個人…
Can't I?
不行嗎
I'll accompany her.
我陪她一起去吧
Megumin?
惠惠?
I can't follow Kazuma, who is now the princess.
我又不能跟著王女殿下的和真
I won't be as meddlesome as those retainers.
我不會像那些家臣一樣管東管西
Really, Sister Megumin?
真的嗎 惠惠姊姊
I did ask you to call me that,
雖然是我要妳這麼叫的
but you can stick with Megumin.
但妳還是叫我惠惠吧
Miss Megumin, thank you.
惠惠小姐 麻煩妳了
Leave it to me.
包在我身上
From how to bargain when shopping
從怎麼殺價買東西
to how to deal with others' provocations,
到怎麼應付別人的挑釁
I will teach you all sorts of things.
我會教妳各式各樣的事
Is it really okay?
真的沒問題嗎
Yay!
耶
Oh no, this is addictive.
不妙 這好像會上癮
Princess Iris.
愛…愛麗絲殿下
Did that man
您是不是又被那個男人
teach you bad things again?
灌輸了什麼不好的知識
Claire, Mr. Kazuma is an outstanding person.
克萊兒 和真先生是很優秀的人
His name could be in a history textbook.
優秀到放進歷史課本裡也行喔
Did he really impart something to you?
他…他真的對您灌輸了什麼嗎
It's better to get rid of him.
果然 還是解決那個男人比較好
Please don't have such frightening thoughts right behind him.
拜託妳別在本人後面 想那種可怕的事
Princess Iris.
愛麗絲殿下
Mr. Mitsurugi.
御劍先生
I've heard that you've again had a great performance.
聽說您這次的表現也很出色
Not at all.
哪裡
It's nothing remarkable.
那沒什麼了不起的
So you can look like that too.
原來妳會露出這種表情啊
Because I consider protecting the citizens
因為我把保護這個國家的人
and Princess Iris as my mission.
和愛麗絲殿下當成我的使命
Claire.
克萊兒
Execute this man who dares to touch my head.
把隨便摸我頭的這個男人處死
What?
什麼
You've been weird since earlier.
您從剛剛開始就不太對勁
What happened?
到底是怎麼了
I'll forgive your disrespect
我就看在克萊兒的面子上
on account of Claire.
原諒你剛才的不敬吧
Now get lost.
快滾吧
Scram now.
好了 快滾吧
Go away.
走開 走開
My…my apologies.
失…失禮了
Heck.
真是的
I'm not strolling through the castle
我在城堡裡漫步
to see you.
不是為了見你
Right, Claire.
對了 克萊兒
Yes.
是
Where is Lalatina?
拉拉蒂娜在哪裡
I want to tease her…
我想盡情捉弄…
She has worked hard in this battle.
她在這次的戰鬥中好像很努力
I want to reward her.
所以我想慰勞拉拉蒂娜
Lord Dustiness got covered in ash
達斯堤尼斯卿在戰鬥中
in the battle.
搞得全身都是灰
She is taking a bath.
現在正在洗澡
Take me there immediately!
立刻帶我過去
I want to join in and wash her back!
我也要一起洗 幫她洗背
How can royalty wash a retainer's back?
王族怎麼能幫家臣洗背
I want to wash your back too.
我也想幫克萊兒洗背
Thank you for your hard work.
感謝妳平時的辛勞
Could it be
難道
you don't like it?
妳不喜歡嗎
How could I not like it?
怎麼會不喜歡
Come on, Princess Iris.
來吧 愛麗絲殿下
Let's go.
我們走吧
Let's go right now.
我們馬上走吧
It's the highest honor.
真是無上的光榮
Come, come.
來吧 來吧
Eh?
奇…奇怪
This lady's gaze upon Iris is…
總覺得這位大姊姊 看著愛麗絲的眼神
Is she from that side?
是那邊的人嗎
I thought she was serious and strict.
我還以為她是認真又嚴謹的傢伙
She is from over there?
原來是那邊的人嗎
Is there no decent female character in this world?
這個世界就沒有像樣的女性角色嗎
But it suits me fine.
不過這樣也好
Princess Iris.
愛麗絲殿下
Are you taking a bath before the banquet?
您是趁宴會之前來洗澡嗎
Princess Iris?
愛麗絲殿下?
I want to wash Lalatina's back, she fought hard in the battle.
我想幫在戰鬥中 表現活躍的拉拉蒂娜洗背
But it seems I'm late.
但是 我好像來晚了
What a pity.
真可惜
Princess Iris's kindness cannot be wasted.
怎…怎麼能辜負愛麗絲殿下的好意
I'll wash it again.
我再洗一次吧
Undressing in front of me?
居…居然在我面前脫衣服
She's too careless.
太大意了
I'm not mentally prepared.
我還沒做好心理準備
Calm down.
冷靜點
Calm down, Satou Kazuma.
冷靜點 佐藤和真
Darkness and you have bathed together before.
你和達克妮絲不是一起 洗過澡的關係嗎
Your face is so red.
您的臉好紅啊
She smells good.
好香喔
No, that's not the point.
不對 重點不是這個
If I have the scent of soap on me,
要是身上留下肥皂的味道
Iris will find out that I took a bath.
愛麗絲就會發現我洗過澡了
Oh my gosh!
我的天啊
It's such a tempting scene.
眼前明明是這麼誘人的景象
Endure.
忍耐
I must endure.
我要忍耐
If she discovered…
要是被發現的話…
Are you feeling unwell?
您身體不舒服嗎
Something has been off since a while ago.
從剛剛開始就不太對勁
I understand
我懂了
why the reincarnated would want this sacred treasure.
為什麼轉生者會想要這個神器
Whatever.
管他的
So what if Iris finds out I took a bath
就算愛麗絲會因為肥皂的味道
because of the soap's scent?
發現我洗過澡又怎樣
The great ancestors of Japan
日本的偉大先人們
left us with this saying,
留下這麼一句話
'Leave tomorrow's matters to tomorrow.'
"明天的事 明天再想就好"
The goddess of fortune, Lady Eris,
幸運女神艾莉絲大人
I am now wholeheartedly grateful
我現在衷心地感謝
for my good luck.
自己的運氣這麼好
Asking for a beating, brat?
欠揍嗎 臭小子
Are you prepared for the consequences?
你做好覺悟了吧
Look, big brother is all disheartened.
你看 大哥都消沉了
I… I'm not disheartened at all.
我…我才沒消沉呢
It's just the first time I've been insulted so harshly.
我只是第一次被人罵得這麼難聽
That's right, you've said it well.
就是這樣 妳說得很好
Crush them with your next sentence.
用下一句話擊潰他們吧
From the moment you strutted with your lackeys,
從你帶著跟班虛張聲勢的那一刻起
you were destined to be a nobody,
就注定是小人物
an overwhelmingly insignificant nobody,
壓倒性的小人物
a waste that can't even contribute to others' points.
是無法讓人提升經驗值的廢物
How dare you look down on me!
竟敢瞧不起我
(Episode 6: Farewell to the Good Life)
(第6集 向美好的 生活說再見)
Welcome.
歡迎光臨 歡迎光臨
Three bowls of Slime Red Bean Soup left.
史萊姆紅豆湯 還剩下三碗喔
Hello, I'm Hans.
您好 我是漢斯
May I have a word?
可以聽我說嗎
Sometimes I wonder…
我有時候會想…